-=圣城家园 SCG-720PG 荣誉出品=-
打佛 作品
bbs.cnscg.com
本片根据真实故事改编
宾州南部斯坦顿
The forecast: plenty of sunshine today
天气预报: 阳光灿烂
with seasonal temperatures,
气温正常
we should reach our normal high over this afternoon.
下午高温会到达华氏82度
Clear skies tonight.
晚上爽朗
Increasing cloudiness tomorrow, sticky and humid.
明天天气转为阴湿
Hey. hey! Come give me a kiss. Be good.
嘿 亲我一下 你要乖乖的
- Bye. - Bye!
- 再见 - 再见!
Have fun!
好好上课!
Cleve, it's 1 955.
克里夫 是1955年
Please re- enter the clubhouse in a more stereotypically animated fashion.
俱乐部里的动画片真是刻板
宾州南部布鲁斯特
Hey. man. you know where I could find Frank Barnes?
法兰克巴恩在哪里?
- Sir? - Frank Barnes.
- 你说什么? - 法兰克巴恩
Good luck.
祝好运
Thanks.
谢谢
Excuse me. I'm looking for Frank Barnes.
不好意思 我要找法兰克巴恩
You found him.
我就是
I'm Will Colson.
我是威尔考森
We're working together today on train 1 206.
我们今天要一起在1206列车工作
- 1 206. - That's the one.
- 1206 - 没错
- That's the profile? - Yeah. Want to take a look?
- 你的简历吗? - 没错 看一下吗?
How you doing?
你好吗?
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗?
No problem.
没问题
I just don't like working in a damn day- care center.
我只是不喜欢在幼稚园工作
Yeah. well. I don't like working at a retirement home. so...
我也不喜欢在养老院工作...
All right. I'll tell you what.
够了
I'm gonna finish my coffee. I'll meet you on the wagon.
我先喝完咖啡 然后车上见
Sounds good.
好
- 1 206. - Yeah. That's the one.
- 1206列车 - 没错
You know that punk's union. right?
你们知道他是工会的人吧?
Heard they just made him a shop steward at the UTU.
他们让他当了谈判代表
First year?
第一年加入?
You know how he got hired? His name's Colson.
你们知道他是怎么被录取的? 他姓考森
His two uncles are running things over at Thornwood
两个叔叔都是高层的人
and his brother's lead welder at Deacon.
兄弟是焊接工主管
The whole family's from Stanton.
整个家族都是斯坦顿来的
That figures.
就是这样
Here. they're shit- canning guys every day.
公司整天都在解雇员工
but you got the right last name and a rookie's pay grade.
但只要姓的对 不管资历如何
you got a job.
就会有工作
宾州北部富勒调度场
What the hell are these guys?
这些家伙在干嘛?
Dewey. Gilleece.
杜伊 葛利
Sorry to break up charm school,
抱歉打断你们
but what the hell is that beast still doing on D- 1 6?
那个柴油车头在D16号轨道干嘛?
I told you I need that track clear.
我不是跟你们说要清空吗?
Relax. buddy. We were just about to move it.
别紧张 我们正要移开
Like hell you are.
少来这一套
I've got 1 50 school students coming in on some field trip on D- 1 6.
有150个学生校外教学要用到D16轨道
I need that track cleared.
我需要轨道清空
D- 1 0's clear. You can set it there.
D10是空的 把车头移过去
All right. All right. settle down. Settle down.
好了 大家安静 大家安静
宾州北部惠岭
Welcome to the Railroad Safety Campaign.
欢迎参加铁路安全讲习
We're a not- for- profit program
这是政府办的活动
designed to educate young people like yourselves about railway safety.
目的是让你们了解铁路安全的重要
Hey. settle down.
大家安静
Show of hands.
举手代表
Who's ridden a train before?
谁有坐过火车?
Me! Me!
我! 我!
All right! All aboard!
好 大家上车!
So what's our day?
今天要做什么?
They got us going on light power.
我们只要调度火车头
We're supposed to pick up 25 cars just past Stanton
过了斯坦顿接25节车厢
then it's pretty much a straight shot through Wilkins.
然后通过威金斯
Any slow orders?
有慢车吗?
- No. - You sure?
- 没有 - 你确定?
They'd be highlighted in red.
有就会用红色标示
No. No slow orders.
没有慢车
All right.
好
Dewey, what the hell is taking you so long?
杜伊 为什么这么久?
It's a 39- car consist. Bunny.
39节车厢
The thing's half a mile long. for Christ's sake.
有半哩长耶
Gilleece. channel up.
葛利 说话
Go for Gilleece.
葛利 收到
You believe this shit?
这太扯了
Hey. hold up. You forgot to tie the air in from the point.
等一下 空气管线没接好
Yeah. so?
那又怎样?
So. you don't have any air brakes.
你没有刹车
You can tie the hoses once we got her parked
我不要听邦尼碎念
and Bunny's quit his bitching.
车停好再弄
Okay.
好
I only got one rule.
我只有一个规矩
One rule only.
唯一一个规矩
You gonna do something. you do it right.
事情要做对
You don't know how to do it. ask me. all right?
不清楚就问 明白吗?
宾州南部布鲁斯特调度场
Likewise. if you need anything from me. you better speak up
如果你需要什么 就问我
'cause you're the conductor.
因为你是列车长
Once we get our freight. it's your train.
我们一上路 车就是你的
I'm just the guy driving it.
我只是驾驶
How long you been out of training?
你训练结束多久?
About four months.
四个月
Four months? Wow. Yeah.
四个月? 哇
Full- on yellow vest rookie.
有够菜的
How long you been railroading?
你在铁道工作多久了?
Twenty- eight years. November 1 3. 1 981. 28 years.
28年 从81年11月13日起
What did you do before that?
你之前做什么的?
Oh. I don't know. A bunch of different jobs.
就一堆工作换来换去
- Yeah? No railroading? - No.
- 没做过铁道? - 没有
Just looking to do something different.
就想做不一样的
Something different?
不一样?
What do you mean. something better?
你是说更好吗?
No. Just...
不...
Different. Just different.
不一样 就换个不一样的
Hey. Dewey. want to pick it up a little bit. jagoff?
杜伊 快一点
I want to have lunch at some point.
我还想要吃完午餐
- Yeah. - Hey.
- 什么事 - 嘿
Your lawyer just called. You got a break.
你的律师刚打来 好消息
The hearing's been moved up to this morning.
听证会改到今天早上
Looks like you'll be going home.
看来你有机会回家了
Well. that's great. but...
那太好了 但是...
Did you tell him I was working?
你有告诉他我在工作吗?
I can't come in.
我来不了
Yeah. yeah. yeah. He said no problem. man.
我说了 他说没问题
- It's looking good. - All right.
- 状况看来不错 - 好的
Call him in an hour or two. see where it's at.
等会帮我再打给他 再告诉我状况
- I will. - And then give me a call.
- 好 - 再打给我
We ready to pull out or what?
我们有没有要出发?
Coming.
马上来
All right.
好
Train's leaving.
火车可不等人的
What's our fuel gauge reading?
油料表读数多少?
Fuel gauge. 2.900.
油料表读数2900
2900!
2.900!
Angle- cock's closed. hand brake's knocked off.
角旋塞关闭 手刹车放开
Good. good. good.
很好 很好
Got all the updated division notices and bulletin orders.
路线资料 内部通知都准备好
The POS releases are in.
POS信息收到
Filled out our time slips. We're good to go.
发车资料记录也填妥 我们可以出发了
Good. All right.
很好 很好
You're at 29 cars. You got 1 0 to go. You're good.
29节 还剩10节 状况不错
Dewey, you got 29. Ten more makes...
杜伊 29节加10节是...
You taking PB- 9 over to D- 1 0?
你要把PB9移到D10 ?
Dewey.
杜伊
Hold your horses.
等一下
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Damn trailing point switch. The track's aligned for D- 1 6.
轨道切换不对 我会往D16去
What's your stopping distance?
要多久才能停下来?
At least 20 cars to a stop. Damn it!
至少要20节车厢长 该死!
Okay. so we back it up and lose a little time.
那我们多花点时间先后退
I'm hopping out.
我下去改
Do not get out of that cab. man!
不要离开驾驶厢!
Don't worry. I'll set the independent.
不用担心 我会设定独立刹车
Dewey! Dewey!
杜伊 杜伊!
无人驾驶
Come on, get back on.
快回去
Dewey! You better get back on!
杜伊 快点回去!
I'm on it. I'm on it.
我过去了
前进
Shit!
该死!
You better get back on. dickhead.
你最好快上车
Hey!
嘿!
Shit!
该死!
Nice job. Dewey!
做得好!
God damn it!
该死!
So now what the hell do we do?
现在我们怎么办?
宾州南部麦尔斯堡调度站
"妮可生日"
Shoot.
该死
Ooh. you're in trouble.
你麻烦大了
Just don't talk about it. Just put your sister on the phone. sweetheart.
别乱说 找你姊接电话
Dad.
爸找你
She doesn't want to talk to you.
她不想跟你说话
Listen. Just tell her I was... I didn't forget. I was just...
就跟她说我没忘 我只是...
I was running late.
我会晚点到
She's got a date tonight.
她晚上有约会
With who?
跟谁?
Just put your sister on the phone.
叫她接电话就对了
Wait. Here she is.
等一下 我叫她接
Nic?
妮琪?
Nicky?
Hello?
喂?
Listen. just...
听着...
Baby, look, I didn't forget. I was...
宝贝 我没...
Frank. the stop blocks are up. Is there a problem?
车头掉转好了 有问题吗?
No. there's no problem. except you got it backwards.
没问题 只是你方向弄反了
Turntable house goes on my end. You're on the ballast.
转盘机房该在我这边 你该在另外一头
On my end.
在我这边
Other than that, no problem. No problem at all.
除此之外 没问题
Like I told you.
我说过
if you don't know something. just ask. That's all.
如果不清楚 就问我
I got it.
了解
I hope so.
最好是
Whatever.
随便你
Excuse me?
你说什么?
This shit. This "Let's make the new guy prove himself" bullshit.
这套"让新人证明自己"的狗屁
I gotta tell you. I've heard it before and it gets old real fast.
我早就听过 我可不吃这一套
Well. that's how it is at the retirement home.
在养老院我们就是这样做
Company wants to get rid of us old heads.
公司想把我们这些老鸟赶走
They give all the jobs to you new guys. you yellow vests.
把工作给你们这些新人 年轻小伙子
I'm not trying to take anything from anybody.
我没有要抢任何人的工作
As reassuring as that is.
不管你怎么说
a lot of guys don't see it that way.
大部分人的看法就是这样
I'm here. I'm walking in right now.
我到了 马上就会进去
I got a car full of donuts for those kids.
带了好几盒甜甜圈给孩子们吃
- A coaster? What train? - Connie?
- 滑行车? 哪一台? - 康妮?
How the hell did this happen?
这是怎么发生的?
It just got away from me.
车就这样跑掉了
It got away from you?
车就这样跑掉了?
It's a train. Dewey. not a chipmunk.
那是火车 不是宠物
I had to leave the cab to throw a switch.
我离开驾驶厢去改轨道开关
- You left the cab? - Yeah.
- 你离开驾驶厢? - 对
And it gets worse.
还不只这样
The air brakes weren't tied on. They aren't tied on. still.
空气刹车没有接上 还没有接上
We've got an unmanned train rolling into opposing traffic
有一辆无人列车逆向在轨道前进
with no air brakes. is that what you're telling me?
还没有刹车?
I set the independent brakes. That'll for sure stop it.
我有设定独立刹车 它迟早会停
How fast is it going?
速度有多快?
No more than 1 0 miles per.
一小时不超过十哩
Okay. Jump on the hi- rail and go after it.
开维修车去追
Now!
立刻去!
Okay. ballbuster.
好 你是老大
Call the field trip!
联络旅游车!
I don't care where they are on the main line.
不管他们到了哪里
they need to get into the nearest siding.
请他们 马上进侧线
RS Campaign. RS Campaign. This is Fuller Yard. Do you copy?
旅游车 这是富勒调度场 请回答
RSC answering dispatch. How can I help you? Over.
控制中心 收到 有何指示
RS Campaign. this is Fuller Yard.
旅游车 这是富勒调度场
We've got unauthorized activity on your track.
轨道上发现未核准的活动
We're gonna need you to divert to a siding at Portville.
请改道到最近的波特维尔侧线
Dispatch. please repeat.
控制中心 请重复
Please repeat. Over.
请重复
What time is train time?
什么时候可以坐火车?
Anytime!
任何时候!
Divert to a siding in Portville. Do you copy?
改道到最近的波特维尔侧线 有没有收到?
I copy. I'll divert into the siding at Portville. Over.
收到 我会改道到波特维尔侧线
Get me 777's cargo information.
给我777号列车的载货资料
I have to call corporate and report this.
我需要通报总公司
Now. Dewey said he applied the independent.
杜伊说他有设定独立刹车
so friction should stop the damn thing after a few miles.
阻力应该会在几哩后让列车停下
Still. we need to alert every northbound train on the mainline.
我们要通知所有主线北行的列车
First 20 miles of track take priority.
20哩范围内的列车优先
I don't care if you're talking about
不管你说的
a spot weld on a Class 3 rip track
是在维修轨道整修火车
or ground operations in Afghanistan. it's all about precision.
或是在阿富汗的行动 精准度最重要
- Right. - Thank you.
- 没错 - 谢谢
- Excuse me. - Sure.
- 不好意思 - 没问题
Hello.
喂
Ned. where are you?
奈德 你在哪里?
Oh. Connie. I'm just driving in now.
康妮 我快到公司了
I got to go.
我要走了
How far are you from milepost 5?
你离五号工作站多远?
Roughly six minutes. traffic contingent.
大约六分钟 这要看交通状况
Great. I need you to haul ass over there
好极了 我需要你马上过去
and throw the siding switch. We got a coaster.
切换轨道 我们有滑行车状况
A coaster? Really?
滑行车? 真的吗?
Yeah. It should roll past MP 5 in about 1 5 minutes.
它应该15分钟后会经过五号站
That should give you enough time to throw the switch.
你有足够的时间切换轨道
get it off the mainline and onto that siding.
让它离开主线进入侧线
You want me to climb onboard and stop it?
你要我爬上车停下它?
What? No. Two hostlers are on the way. Just throw the switch. Ned.
不用 有两个工作人员过去了 你只要切换轨道就好
Roger that.
收到
You can always count on him to be late.
他永远都迟到
I'll see you later.
我晚点回来
See you!
再见!
Yeah, I can get you where you need to go
'Cause I'm a country boy
What do we do when we get to a railroad crossing?
我们到了平交道该怎么办?
Stop. Iook and listen!
停、看、听!
I can't hear you!
我听不到!
Stop. Iook and listen!
停、看、听!
宾州南部斯坦顿弯道
限速15哩
You from Stanton?
你是斯坦顿人?
Born and raised. Yeah?
在这里出生长大
My whole family's from Stanton.
我们家族都是斯坦顿人
Married?
结婚了?
Yeah.
对
Well. sort of. It's a long story.
算吧 说来话长
We got a long day.
我们有大把时间
How about you? You married?
你呢? 结婚了?
Short story. Once.
说来话短 一次
Got two beautiful daughters. though. 1 8. 1 9.
有两个宝贝女儿 18岁跟19岁
They are both waitressing. trying to work their way through college.
她们都是服务生 打工念大学
- Oh. yeah? - Yeah.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Where at? - Hooters.
- 在哪里打工? - 辣妹参厅
Hooters. You know? All right.
辣妹参厅? 你知道吗? 好
That's right. Hooters. Wipe that grin off your face.
别怀疑 就是辣妹参厅 把脸上那个奇怪笑容收起来
- I'm a fan. - Yeah.
- 我很喜欢那个地方 - 当然
You're blushing.
你脸都红了
I'm used to it.
我习惯了
Connie. Corporate on line 2.
康妮 总公司在二线
This is Connie Hooper at Fuller Yard.
我是富勒调度场的康妮胡波
I'll hold.
我会等
Did I hear right? You've got a coaster?
听说你有滑行车 真的吗?
Yeah. This sort of thing happens. We're on it.
偶发事件 我们在处理了
Won't it trip a relay?
停的下来吗?
Listen. I need to speak to Mr. Galvin directly.
听着 我要直接跟盖文先生报告
I see. Can you have him call me. then?
我了解 可以请他回电吗?
No. I'm about to review the cargo shipment myself.
不 我正要看货物清单
Who the hell are you?
你是谁?
I'm here for the Railroad Safety Campaign.
我来做铁路安全讲习
Scott Werner. FRA Region 2. Federal Safety Inspector.
史考特华纳 联邦铁路局第二区安全检查员
I'm supposed to give a presentation to the children.
我来替学童上课
- go over some basic stuff. That's great. - Hey. Bunny? Bunny!
- 讲一些基本安全知识 - 嘿 邦尼!
Can you help me out here?
帮我一下好吗?
Okay. see this guy right there?
你看到那个人了吗?
He's gonna tell you where to sit.
他会带你去坐下
Track geometry. alignment...
轨道地理学 等等...
Thank you so much. I brought some gauges...
谢谢 我带了测量仪来...
The kids are gonna love that. It's great.
小朋友会喜欢 太好了
God damn it. Where the hell is this thing?
他妈的 这东西到底在哪里?
液态酚 危险物质
Bunny? I need to know exactly what's in cars 7 to 1 0.
邦尼 我要知道7到10车装什么
Get a hold of the shipper. please.
请帮我联络寄货人
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑?
Where's the train?
火车呢?
Where does it look like the goddamn train is?
你说火车在哪里?
It's not here! What are you doing out here?
我不知道 你在这里干什么?
Do I look like I got a train hidden in my back pocket?
我有可能把火车藏在口袋里吗?
Bunny. get me Connie. It's Ned.
邦尼 帮我接给康妮 我是奈德
Get behind us. jackass.
到后面去 SB
- Did you get here too late? - Don't give me that shit.
- 你太慢到了 - 少来这一套
You two numbnuts are always screwing up.
你们两个白痴老把事情搞砸
You switched the track that was supposed to get the train on the right track.
你调换轨道了吗?
Connie. Yeah. it's Ned.
康妮 我是奈德
Did you throw that switch yet?
你把开关弄好没?
Yeah. six minutes ago. but your train. it's not here.
6分钟前就弄好了 但没看到火车
I thought it might be going a little slower than you guessed,
我以为车速比你想的慢
but these two numbnuts that you sent.
但你派来的两个白痴刚出现
they just showed up and they ain't seen it. either.
他们也没看到
Are you saying our train's already passed?
你是说火车已经过去了?
Yes. ma'am. That'd be my guess.
我想是这样
It's not a coaster. That train's under power.
它不是滑行车 火车有动力
That'd be my guess. too.
我也是这么认为
- Put Dewey on the phone. - Sure.
- 叫杜伊接电话 - 好的
She wants to talk to you. asshole.
她要跟你说话 浑蛋
Yeah.
好的
I need you to rally every cell in that brain of yours.
我要你用力地想
When you applied the independent.
你设定独立刹车的时候
was the throttle in the forward position?
油门在前进的状态吗?
Yeah. I had to get it moving!
没错 我要让它移动!
In what position was the throttle set?
油门放在什么位置?
Damn it. Dewey. what position?
该死 在什么位置?
Connie. the throttle was in notch 8. full power.
油门在第八格全速前进
Okay? It was 39 cars!
它拖了39节车!
Okay.
好
Take the southbound track. Catch up.
往南跟上去
See if it's still going slow enough for one of you to climb on.
看你们能不能爬上去
You have got until milepost 1 3 before the track splits.
你要等到13号哩程标轨道才会分开
Let me talk to Ned again.
让我跟奈德说话
Nice job. asshole!
做得好 浑蛋!
Ned. I want you to get back in your car and follow the mainline. Okay?
奈德 我要你回到车上跟着主线 明白吗?
I want a set of eyes on that train.
我要你盯住列车
You got them. Roger that.
没问题 了解
I can't hear you!
我听不到!
Railroad Safety Campaign!
铁路安全非常重要!
宾州南部锌工厂
You're good.
没问题
Keep it coming. 50.
还有50尺
20 feet.
20尺
Slow down.
减速
All right. you're good.
搞定了
Yeah. What's going on?
杰西 怎么了?
You got a minute?
可以讲话吗?
I thought he said it was looking good.
他不是说状况很好?
That's what he thought.
他本来这么想
Turns out the judge they assigned was a real hard- ass.
但是遇上的法官非常难搞
You gotta be kidding me.
别开玩笑了
Look. the restraining order is being continued for another 30 days.
保护令又被延长了30天
Thirty days? What am I supposed to do for 30 days?
30天? 我该怎么办?
Stay away from my kid?
不能接近孩子?
And then there's another hearing after that. I guess.
还会有一个听证会
What's taking you so long. Will?
威尔 怎么这么慢?
You call that lawyer. you can tell him
你打电话给那个律师
he can stick it up his ass. I got to go.
叫他去死 我得做事了
Will, pick up the radio.
威尔 拿起无线电
Will. pick up the radio. Over.
威尔 拿起无线电 完毕
Are you there?
你在吗?
Yeah.
在
Yeah. Get off the phone. knock off the hand brakes.
别再讲电话了 放开手刹车
get up here. It's time to go. We got work to do.
快上来 该走了 还有活要干
Copy.
收到
No. it's definitely under power.
确定有动力
We're not sure of the exact speed yet.
但车速还不确定
I thought all these trains had some sort of dead- man brake.
这些车不是都有紧急刹车装置?
There's a wand the engineer has to hit periodically
但要靠人力启动
or the air brakes are automatically applied.
不然还能靠空气刹车
Unfortunately. this train's air brakes were disconnected.
不幸的是 空气刹车没有连接
Sir, I would gladly explain the particulars of locomotive operation to you
我很乐意解释火车头基本操作
if we had time. but right now I really need your assistance
如果有足够的时间 但现在我需要您的协助
posting officers at all the mainline crossings.
派遣警员到所有主线上的平交道
One question.
一个问题
How do you all plan to stop it?
你们打算如何让车停下来?
We're working on it.
我们还在想办法
Go. go. go! The split's coming up!
快快 前面又要分轨了!
Are you sure you can do this?
你确定上的去?
Just get alongside of the cab.
开到驾驶厢旁就对了
Get up alongside of it!
开到驾驶厢旁边!
I'm trying!
我在努力了!
Go. go. go!
快点!
Remember. we don't have a lot of track!
记住 我们没剩多少轨道了!
You got it. go. go!
可以了 快上去!
Dewey!
杜伊!
It's too fast! Back it up!
太快了 慢一点!
Come on. Dewey! Go back!
杜伊 慢一点!
Jump. Gilleece! Do it!
葛利 快上去!
Get in! Watch out!
快回车里 小心!
So now what the hell do we do?
这下我们该怎么办?
How many cars are we supposed to cut in?
我们该挂多少节车厢?
Twenty. Why?
20节 怎么了?
Twenty cars. okay.
20节 好
See the switch stand up ahead of us?
有看到前面的开关标志吗?
The switch stand. yeah? Uh- huh.
开关标志?
Take a look in the rear view mirror. You see the one behind us?
看后视镜 看到后面那个了吗?
Way back there. You see it? Uh- huh.
最后面那边 看到了吗?
There's exactly 21 cars between the two stands.
两个标志间刚好是21节的距离
Don't ask me how I know.
别问我怎么知道的
So why is it that
那么为什么
there's still more than four and a half cars that are yet to clear?
还有4节半的车厢在距离外?
Because I...
因为我...
Excuse me?
你说什么?
- Because I cut... - Because what?
- 因为我... - 因为什么?
I cut in too many cars.
因为我挂了太多车厢
Cut in too many cars. huh?
挂了太多车厢?
Maybe if you weren't on my ass the whole time.
如果不是你一直找我麻烦
I might be able to think straight and do my job.
我就能好好思考做好工作
What do you mean. "Maybe. if I..."
你什么意思 "也许 假如我..."
You been on my ass this whole trip! You're blaming it on me?
你把事情推到我身上?
I'm just saying. pick a goddamn job!
我只是说 找一个工作!
I got my job! You pick one!
我有工作了! 二选一!
I pull the throttle. you pull the pin! It's one or the other!
弄油门或者是插销! 二选一!
You're five pins too many.
你去弄插销 你多了五个插销
Pull the pins. You're right. pull the pins.
弄好插销 你说的对
I've had my training! All right?
我有通过训练!
Yeah. but we're out here in the real world. This ain't training.
但这是实际上阵 不是训练
In training. they just give you an F. Out here. you get killed.
训练不合格 顶多被当掉 这里玩真的 没搞好你就没命
- I screwed up. okay? - Yes. you did.
- 我错了 好吗? - 你的确错了
Stop and roll back and I'll cut the empties.
停车 后退 我把空车拿掉
Roll back?
后退?
Oh. Lord.
天啊
We can't stop out here on the main.
我们在主线上不能停车
We're more than a mile out on the main.
已经离开一哩了
more than a mile to the next stop.
离下一站还有一哩多
You don't take a consist this size that distance in reverse.
这样的长度距离不能后退
Fine. Then we'll make the turn at the next siding.
好 那我们到一个侧线再倒转
The next siding's not for 1 0 miles.
下一个侧线还有十哩远
We do that. we're late. I don't run late.
那样会迟到 我不想迟到
Just green- sheet it and we'll move on.
记录下来就好
Come on. We green- sheet it and it's my ass! Cut me some slack.
算了 做纪录就会害到我!
What do you mean. it's your ass? You're a Colson.
什么意思 害到你? 你姓考森耶
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
那是什么意思?
That means you can call your uncle and they'll take care of it.
意思是 你叔叔会帮你
Is that what this is about?
你是因为这样找我麻烦吗?
No. it's about the five cars too many.
不是 是因为多了5节车厢
We're gonna stop. roll back and cut those empties!
那我们就停车 后退 放掉多的车厢!
This may be your engine. but it's my goddamn train.
这是你的车头 但列车是我的
- Yes. it is. - I'm the goddamn conductor!
- 这是你的列车没错 - 我才是列车长!
- That's true. - 1206, check in.
- 没错 - 呼叫1206列车
I'll write you up and green- sheet your ass.
我要打你的小报告
- Will you? - How about that?
- 满意了? - 这样如何?
1206, this is dispatch. What's your location? Over.
1206列车 请回报位置 结束
- Something's funny? - No.
- 什么东西这么好笑 - 没事
What the hell are you laughing at? What are you laughing at?
那你他妈的在笑什么? 那你在笑什么?
Because it's funny. You're a funny guy.
因为很有趣 你是个有趣的人
Well- trained. but funny. Yeah. this is 1 206.
训练有素 但是好笑 这里是1206列车
We're 60 miles from Wilkins.
我们距离威尔森60哩
Forty minutes out of Fuller Yard.
距离富勒调度场40分钟
Negative. 1 206. Clear your train at the next siding
要求拒绝 请在下一个侧线离开
宾州芬德雷中央调度中心
until further instructed. Over.
等候进一步指示
What's up?
发生什么事?
There's an unmanned train out of Fuller, on the northbound track. Over.
富勒有一辆无人列车正在北行中
On our track?
跟我们同一轨道?
A coaster?
滑行车?
1 206. we don't have all the details yet.
我们没有进一步的消息
Just proceed to the next siding and hold tight. Over.
请前往下一条侧线
Next siding's not for 1 0 miles.
下一条侧线还有10哩
Affirmative, 1206.
了解 1206列车
Just get in that siding and sit tight
请尽速前往侧线
until we give you the all- clear. Over.
等候指示
Affirmative.
收到
It's coming right at us.
它正对我们而来
More word on that runaway freight train in rural Pennsylvania.
有关宾州失控列车的进一步消息
The train, A WVR777,
列车编号AwvR 777
otherwise known as 777,
简称777
Ieft Fuller Yard in northern PA
今早大约八点离开
sometime before 8: 00 a. m. this morning
宾州北部的富勒调度场
and no one was onboard.
车上无人控制
Live, local, late- breaking.
最新当地消息
The engineer, they say, made an error in controlling the train.
消息指出驾驶操控判断错误
Before leaving the locomotive,
离开车厢前
he intended to apply the independent brakes.
他想启动独立刹车
And then by the time he realized his mistake,
等他发现错误时
the train was going too fast for him to climb back on.
列车速度已经太快无法再上车
We're being told now by a spokesperson
据铁路管理局
for the Public Utilities Commission
官方发言人表示
that this employee will be held accountable.
驾驶须承担所有责任
- Connie? - Yeah.
- 康妮? - 在
Headquarters is on the phone. It's Galvin.
总公司来电 盖文在线上
Mr. Galvin. how are you?
盖文先生 你好吗?
God damn it. How could this happen?
见鬼 这怎么可能发生?
宾州匹兹堡AwvR总部
It's an unfortunate combination of human error and bad luck.
这是人为错误与衰运的组合
Luck?
运气?
I was a yardmaster for 1 0 years. Ms. Hooper.
我当过调度场主管十年
Luck has no business in a rail yard.
运气在火车这一行不该存在
What are we worried about in terms of cargo?
载货物有需要担心的吗?
Well. obviously. the diesel fuel's a concern.
当然 油料需要担心
No, I said cargo.
不 我在问货物
Okay. well. cars 7 through 1 0
7到10号
and 1 6 through 1 9 are carrying a chemical called molten phenol.
16到19号列车 载运了化学原料液态酚
We're still trying to connect with the shipper
我们还在联系寄货人
to determine exactly what that is.
了解它的用途
It's used in the manufacture of glue.
那是用来生产黏剂的
Can you hold on one moment?
能请你等一下吗?
You know about molten phenol?
你懂液态酚的用途?
Yes.
对
Mr. Galvin. we have an FRA inspector here.
盖文先生 现场有一位联邦铁路局的代表
May I put you on speaker?
我可以用扩音吗?
Region 2 Federal Safety Inspector Scott Werner. How can I help?
我是第二区安全检查员史考特华纳 有什么可以帮忙?
Just tell me what you know about molten phenol.
快告诉我这玩意的用途
Well. it's serious stuff. Very toxic. highly combustible.
它是危险物质 毒性很强 非常易燃
Oh, that's terrific.
太好了
Hooper. get state police back on the line.
胡波 请联络州警
Make sure they got a HazMat team briefed and ready.
请他们派遣危险物质处理小组
And ask them to put a spotter chopper over 777.
派直升机跟紧777
I take it you've sided all rail traffic?
你应该已经清除线上的列车?
On our end, yes. Brewster's notifying its own.
我们的都通知了 布鲁斯特那边会通知他们的列车
Sir.
长官
how are we going to handle this?
我们该怎么处理?
I mean. this train is en route to pass
列车会经过...
through some highly populated areas.
人口密集的区域
We're having a strategy call in about two minutes.
我们两分钟后会开应变电话会议
All right. I'll be ready.
我会准备好
You won't be on the call. Ms. Hooper.
你不需要参加会议 胡波
- Excuse me? - You'll be advised.
- 什么? - 结论会通知你
For now. coordinate with local authorities.
你的当务之急是协调当地各单位
God knows we gotta have over 1 00 crossings that need to be secured.
有超过一百个平交道需要控管
One hundred and seventy- three.
共173个
Railroad crossings.
平交道
Between here and AWVR substation in Brewster.
从这里到布鲁斯特分站
Listen. Mr. Galvin.
听着 盖文先生
this train is half a mile long and is traveling at speed into population
这列车的长度半哩
with eight freight cars of hazardous chemicals
载运八节有毒物质和五千加仑柴油
and 5, 000 gallons of diesel fuel.
加速前往人口密集区域
Sir, we're not just talking about a train here.
这不是一般的列车
We're talking about a missile the size of the Chrysler Building.
这是有如101大楼般的巨大飞弹
So. what is your point. Ms. Hooper?
你想讲什么?
My point is after it crosses through Findlay.
一旦它通过芬德雷
there's about 1 2 miles of vacant farmland.
会经过12哩的农地
but after that. it's nothing but town after town
但之后一路到斯坦顿
all the way to Stanton.
全都是住宅区
We have a very limited window here.
我们手上的时间不多
So. what are you suggesting we do. derail it?
你建议让它脱轨吗?
Yes. sir. I am.
是的
While we still can.
趁我们还有机会的时候
Mr. Galvin. I understand that's gonna cost the company a lot of money...
我知道这样成本很大...
Do you think?
你知道多少吗?
Ms. Hooper. we're not gonna intentionally destroy one of our own trains.
我们不可能摧毁自己的列车
Not when we can still stop it.
我们还有机会让列车停止
We can avoid a lot of collateral...
这样可以避免...
I'm going to extend you my last ounce of good will
我就当你刚才的建议是出于好心
and pretend this conversation never happened.
我会当做这段对话没有发生过
He thinks I'm worried about my job.
他以为我怕我保不住饭碗
宾州北部芬德雷
Ma'am. please stay in your van.
请留在车内
- Come on. - Please get back into the van.
- 来吧 - 请回到车上
Can you please tell us what's going on?
谁能告诉我发生什么事了?
Every crossing's closed off for 20 miles.
20哩内的所有平交道都封锁了
Ma'am. for your safety. please get back into your van.
夫人 为了你的安全 请回到车上
I'm not getting back in the vehicle.
我不回去
We need to know what's going on.
我们要知道发生什么事
Guys. get out of there. There's a train coming.
快点离开 列车来了
Hurry!
快点!
Hurry! It's coming!
快点 列车来了!
Come on. We got to go.
该走了
Get out of there! Move it!
让开 列车来了 快点!
Get out of the way!
闪开!
1 206 to dispatch. Over.
1206呼叫中心
- What's wrong? - What's wrong?
- 怎么了? - 怎么了?
We're not gonna fit in that siding. that's what's wrong.
我们没办法进去那个侧线
1 206 to dispatch. Over.
1206呼叫中心
1 206. are you in the siding yet?
1206 你进侧线了没?
What's your location?
你的位置在哪里?
No, we're not in the hole. We're not gonna make it, can't do it.
不 还没 我们进不去
Too much train.
太多车厢了
I'm gonna need you to realign the switch
我需要你更换轨道
so we can proceed to the next siding.
让我们前往下一个侧线
1 206. you have to get off the main. Over.
1206 你需要马上离开主线
I understand that. but you gotta understand this.
我了解 但你也要了解
we're not going to fit.
我们进不去
1206, stand by.
1206 稍等
That siding's a good 3.000 feet. end to end.
那个侧线有3千尺长
Check your timetable.
时刻表上面
it's gonna tell you the siding is 4111 feet.
写的是4111尺
But that's signal to signal.
但那是两边号志间的总长
In reality. it's more like 2.500 feet.
实际上大约是2500尺
You add those five cars that you picked up...
加上你多挂的五节车厢...
We can fit.
可以进去
No, we won't fit.
不 进不去
Dispatch. this is 1 206.
1206呼叫中心
Can you tell me where the nearest rip track is?
请告知最近的维修轨道位置
1 206. there's one in 6.2 miles. How fast are you going?
6.2哩后有一个 你的速度多快?
55 miles an hour.
551里
1 206. go faster. Over.
开快一点
Why? Is that coaster still on the main?
为什么 那台滑行车还在线上?
1206, 777 is not a coaster. I repeat, it is not a coaster. Over.
1206 777不是滑行车 重复 不是滑行车
You're telling me it's under power?
你是说它有动力?
Get in the goddamn siding.
我们需要 马上进侧线
1206, stand by.
1206 稍等
1 206. if you're going for it. that rip track is confirmed vacant.
1206 如果你要尝试 维修轨道是空的
It's your call, Frank.
你决定 法兰克
We need to throw the switch if you're staying on.
如果你要继续下去 需要更改轨道
We're not staying on! Pull the brake. Frank.
不继续 就拉刹车
We pull the brake and side up. I crash.
拉刹车进侧线就会出乱子
I know what the hell I'm doing.
我是老法师了
- Bullshit! You're gonna get us killed. - Hey!
- 胡扯 你会害死我们! - 嘿
1206, I need an answer. Over.
1206 我需要答案
Realign the switch.
请切换轨道
Over.
完毕
The train was just going with no one in it. Just took off.
当时里面没有人 就开走了
We were yelling on the radio earlier,
我们说列车会经过这里
there's a runaway train coming through.
列车要来了
It could be coming to our town next
接下来会经过我们镇上
and the high school's right next to those train tracks.
学校很接近铁路
Just a few moments ago,
不久前
a train came barreling down these tracks...
一辆失控列车高速经过...
We're still going over the numbers.
我们还在计算数字
but should 777 derail. we're looking at a major disaster.
但如果777脱轨 就会造成极大灾难
If even one of those HazMat cars blew.
任何一节危险车厢爆炸
it could easily decimate an entire town.
就可以夷平一个城镇
That train is carrying eight of them.
列车上总共有八节危险车厢
Can you please explain to our viewers what you witnessed...
能说说你看到的情况吗...
Environmental liability. track damage. car and locomotive loss.
环境和轨道赔偿加上列车损坏
We're looking at a projected cost easily over $1 00 million.
我们预估损失将超过1亿美金
And the resulting stock devaluation?
预估的股票跌幅呢?
Our projections indicate it could be in the 30 to 40% range.
跌幅应该在三成到四成中间
I say we go with Mr. Galvin's option.
我同意进行盖文的计划
I've already prepped our substation in Brewster.
我已经联络好布鲁斯特分站
They just need a go- ahead.
只需要命令就可以进行
You have it.
进行吧
Okay. everybody out.
大家可以离开了
Hoffman. you stay here.
奥克曼留下
Baker. get me a track schematic. Fuller to Stanton. please.
贝克 把富勒到斯坦顿间的轨道图给我
This is Owens.
我是欧文斯
7 1. 70. 7 1 on the gun.
71哩 雷射枪显示时速70到71哩
So the red means?
红点的意思是?
777 blew through a signal.
777的路径
Everything in red means trouble on the mainline.
红点代表麻烦
That's a lot of red.
红点也太多了吧
Connie, Mr. Galvin on line 2.
康妮 盖文先生2线找
This is Connie Hooper.
我是康妮胡波
Have all the mainline crossings been closed?
主线上的所有平交道都关闭了吗?
Yes, I've been coordinating with PSP.
是的 我请州警协助执行了
Do we have a strategy in place?
我们有对应方式了吗?
It's already underway.
已经在进行中
宾州中部基丁峰
By the activity level behind me,
我后方的阵仗显示
it is evident that a plan to stop the runaway train is underway,
他们正在尝试停下失控列车
but so far, no one at AWVR is commenting.
但目前铁路公司没有任何回应
We just witnessed A WVR employee Ryan Scott
铁路公司员工雷恩史考特
boarding one of the rescue helicopters.
登上其中一架救援直升机
He is a 22- year- old Marine vet who has just returned from Afghanistan.
这位前陆战队员刚从阿富汗回国
- What the hell is this? - I need a police escort now!
- 这是怎么回事 - 我需要警察前导!
- It says here you're a welder. - Lead welder.
- 这上面说你是焊接工 - 焊接工主管
Listen. buddy. I don't got a lot of time.
听着 老兄 我没有多少时间
You can call my yardmaster. Connie Hooper!
你们可以联络我主管 康妮胡波!
- Connie sent you? - That's what I said.
- 康妮派你来的? - 没错
I need your help.
我需要你帮忙
1206, this is dispatch.
中心呼叫1206
1 206. we ran the math. At over 2.000. you wouldn't have fit.
我们计算过了 你们的长度超过两千尺 进不去
Good call. Over.
你的决定是对的
Thank you. but I need to know where that oncoming train is.
谢谢 我需要知道那辆列车的位置
How far away is it?
它距离我们多远?
1206, we're not exactly sure.
1206 我们不确定
You're not sure? Well. find out!
你们不确定? 快点弄清楚啊!
I'm high above central Pennsylvania. This train got away...
我在宾州中部的高空...
Emergency responders want to halt all activity near the line
警方封锁了
and possibly evacuate all homes
铁路1哩内的区域
within a mile radius of the tracks.
并考虑疏散其中的居民
There's thousands of gallons of fuel onboard, which is highly flammable.
列车载有几千加仑的易燃油料
But we're still awaiting word on that.
我们等候进一步消息
This is Galvin's strategy?
这就是盖文的计划?
Looks like they're putting a train in front of 777
看来他们试图要用另一辆车档在777前
in an attempt to slow it down.
让它减速
Now, they are sending a chopper with Ryan Scott
接着派出直升机载雷恩过去
and the railroad company is still refusing to comment.
铁路公司仍然拒绝回应
We've just learned that 26- year rail company veteran Judd Stewart
我们刚刚得知有26年经验的机师杰德
is at the controls of the engine
驾驶着
that is in front of the runaway train.
前方的火车
This is Connie Hooper from Fuller Yard.
我是康妮胡波
Is this your guy coming off the helicopter?
你的人要从直升机下来吗?
Still holding at 55.
目前速度55哩
Get her down to 40 and keep braking.
减速到40 继续刹车
Shit!
该死!
That's it. Keep going. Keep slowing.
做的好 继续减速
Get her down to 40 and we'll set our boy down.
到了40哩我们就派人下去
Unbelievable!
真是令人无法相信!
Do this!
一定要成功!
Come on.
快点
...incredibly dangerous...
...太惊险了...
Do this. Judd. come on!
杰德 加油!
I'm under 40. Is he on yet?
低于40哩了 他上去了没?
Now!
往下!
Looks like Marine Ryan Scott has been injured.
看来雷恩受伤了
It's a no- go. Slow down!
没有成功 减速!
Just keep braking. Try to slow it. Try to get 777 off the main.
继续减速 尽量让777离开主线
Switch has been thrown.
轨道已经切换
Slow down. God damn it!
该死的东西 慢下来啊!
Don't side it yet! It's going too fast.
不能切换到侧线 速度太快了
Bail! Bail! Bail!
跳车!
Holy shit!
我的天啊!
Maybe it derailed.
列车可能脱轨了
Wow! I can't believe how crazy that was.
我无法形容刚刚有多夸张
Oh. my God! Galvin. you asshole!
我的天啊 盖文 你这个混蛋!
Fuller Yard. Fuller Yard. This is 1 206.
富勒调度场 这是1206
We're passing milepost 52. heading northbound on the Main 1.
我们正经过52号哩程标 在主线上往北前进
1 206. who am I speaking with?
1206 我在跟哪位说话
Frank Barnes. the engineer.
法兰克巴恩 机师
This is Connie Hooper. yardmaster at Fuller.
我是康妮胡波 富勒主管
Why are you still on the mainline?
为什么你还在主线上?
We were directed to a siding that's a no- go.
我们本要进入侧线但没成功
We're heading to a rip track just past milepost 5- 0.
接下来要进入50号标志的维修轨道
We need to know the location of your yard's train.
我需要知道你们列车的位置
It just passed milepost 47.
它刚经过47号哩程标
Holy shit.
这下糟了
They tried to side it. but it jumped the switch and derailed the lash- up.
他们想让它进入侧线但失败了 导引车因此脱轨翻覆
Lash- up? Who was driving?
导引车? 谁是驾驶?
The engineer, a 26- year rail company veteran,
拥有26年资历的机师杰德史都华
was killed earlier today in Keating Summit, central Pennsylvania.
在基丁峰丧生
Judd Stewart.
杰德史都华
Stewart?
史都华?
You said Stewart?
你说史都华?
Judd Stewart. an engineer from Brewster.
杰德史都华 来自布鲁斯特的机师
You know him?
你认识他?
What's your power on the point?
你车头有多少马力?
5.000 horses. She's not a hotshot.
5000匹 它没有很强
but she's still got some life left in her. over.
但还算有力
Give her all you got. Tell Galvin we got two guys out on the mainline
让它好好表现 告诉盖文有两个公司的人在主线上
about to play chicken with our train.
准备跟我们的车对撞
- We tried to stop it. We blew it. - What?
- 我们试过但失败了 - 怎么了?
That train's got to go down.
火车得被摧毁
The only question is how to minimize the damage.
问题是要怎么减低损伤
Quiet!
大家安静!
We just learned there is yet another train on this track,
我们刚得知有另一辆列车在轨道上
headed directly at the runaway.
正朝着失控列车过去
What the hell is this?
这是什么?
We gotta learn about it on damn TV?
我们竟然要看电视才知道?
Nicole. Listen. don't hang up. Don't hang up.
妮琪 听着 别挂电话
Dad. I'm busy. Okay?
爸 我正在忙
Okay, I understand.
我了解
Dad? I just wanted to tell you I love you.
我只是想告诉你我爱你们而已
that's all. Okay. fine! Dad. what's wrong?
别肉麻了 爸 发生什么事?
Nothing. nothing. I just...
没事 我只是...
Dad. what's wrong?
爸 怎么了?
Just tell your sister I love you both. okay? I got to go.
告诉你妹妹我爱你们 好吗? 我得挂了
What's wrong?
怎么了?
1 206. how are you holding up?
1206 你们还好吗?
About a half a mile from that rip track. Over.
距离维修轨道还有半哩
Chances are you're going to see 777's nose any minute now.
你们随时会看到777的车头
Affirmative.
了解
Why are you braking?
为什么要刹车?
Trust me. If we head in this hot. we'll tear right off the track.
相信我 速度太快我们就会脱轨
Oh. Jesus.
天啊
Get her down to 40 and brace yourself.
减速到40 小心碰撞
You need to get at least 1 0 cars into the siding.
得想办法让十节车厢进入侧线
Yes!
太好了!
Frank, go to 6. Frank, go to 6.
法兰克 切换到六频道
Yeah. I'm at 6. Go.
我在六频道 请说
They're evacuating Arklow.
他们要疏散阿克罗镇
They're going to derail the train.
他们要让列车脱轨
What are they using?
他们要用什么?
Standard DRE.
标准脱轨设备
Yeah. a portable derailer.
移动式脱轨装置
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
I got a look at that train's last coupler knuckle. it was open.
那辆车最后一个连接器看来是开的
We take off right now. we get back on the main.
我们现在出发 我们回到主线上
we can chase it down in reverse.
就能倒退追上列车
Chase? Whoa. wait a minute.
追? 等等
The only way to stop that kind of power. grab it by the tail.
要阻止这种动力只能抓住列车尾
boom. gun it in the opposite direction.
往反方向拉
We can't just chase it down. If it goes down.
我们不能冒险 万一列车脱轨
we're gonna be a wreck on a wreck.
我们就惨了
Doesn't matter. There's a good chance the derailer won't work.
不重要 列车应该不太可能会脱轨
It's called a derailer. for Christ's sake!
那东西都已经叫脱轨器了!
That's what they do! A train that size
它的作用就是让火车脱轨
going that fast. it will vaporize anything that gets in its way.
这么巨大又爆速的列车 只要被它撞到就会人问蒸发
Bullshit! They wouldn't use it if...
狗屁 没把握他们就不会用
They're wrong. all right? They're wrong.
他们错了 好吗? 他们错了
Are you in or are you out?
你到底来不来?
You want to get yourself killed. you do it alone.
你想找死就自己去
You know what? Ask your wife what she thinks.
问问你老婆看她怎么想
Wait!
等一下!
If you're right and that derailer fails.
如果脱轨器没作用
what are the odds it makes it to Stanton?
列车开到斯坦顿的机率有多大?
You saw the train. What do you think?
你刚刚有看到 你说呢?
1 206. this is Connie Hooper. Are you there?
1206 我是康妮胡波 你们在吗?
1 206. Over.
1206 请说
Just wanted to see how you boys are doing.
只是想问问你们的状况
We're doing about 60 mile an hour. Connie.
现在时速大约60哩 康妮
Sorry? Frank. I don't understand.
什么? 法兰克 我不懂
We're going after your train.
我们要去追你的列车
1206, I'm not hearing you.
1206 我不懂你意思
The rear knuckle was left open.
车尾的连接器是开的
so if we can catch up. we can tie it on to our locomotive.
如果我们追得上 就可以接到我们的车头
try and slow down 777.
让777慢下来
Frank. you can't.
法兰克 你不能这样
We already are.
我已经做了
Portable derailer's not gonna cut it. Connie.
携带式脱轨器没有用的
Who said anything about a derailer?
谁说要用脱轨器了?
Dispatch. they said that they're evacuating Arklow.
调度场说要撤离阿克罗镇的居民
Two plus two is four.
猜都猜的到
- It's Ned. He said he's still following... - No. No. No.
- 奈德打来 他说还在追踪... - 不
Tell him I'll call him back. Get me Galvin. now.
告诉他我会回电 马上打给盖文
Frank. that train's carrying 30.000 gallons of toxic chemicals.
车上有三万加仑的有毒物质
They had a window before. but that train's going into populated areas.
刚刚本来有机会的 但火车正开往人口稠密的地区
There's no way they'd derail it now.
现在不能让它脱轨了
Are you sure about that?
你确定吗?
Look. Iet me make some calls.
让我先打电话确定
Make some calls. Please.
请打电话确定
What do you think? Do you think they can catch up?
你觉得他们能赶上吗?
Possibly. But even if they do.
有可能 但就算他们赶上了
we're talking about coupling at 1 0 times the normal speed. in reverse.
他们要在一般速度快十倍下连结 还是反方向
I thought you were in favor of derailment.
我以为你比较想让车脱轨
Yeah. when they were in the middle of nowhere. not now.
那时列车还在偏僻的地方
It's just town after town out there!
但现在列车要开到城镇里了!
Mr. Galvin says he'd have to call you back.
盖文说要再打给你
This is Connie Hooper for Mr. Galvin.
我是康妮胡波 找盖文先生
Mr. Galvin is in a meeting.
他在开会
Then maybe you can tell me. Is the company planning on derailing 777?
那么你来告诉我 公司决定要让777脱轨吗?
Last I heard. Galvin was dead set against it.
之前我听说的是盖文死命反对
I'm sorry, I'd really like to help you, Ms. Hooper.
抱歉 恕我爱莫能助
But I'm not at liberty to give you that information.
我没有办法代表公司回应
No. of course you're not at liberty to.
不 你当然无权这么做
Frank's right.
法兰克说对了
What's the fastest you've taken a single engine like this?
这种单引擎可以开多快?
- Unattached? - Yeah.
- 没挂车厢吗? - 没错
Fifty. 55.
50到55哩
Of course. I was going forward.
那是往前进的话
1206, you there?
1206 听到了吗?
This is 1 206. over.
1206回话 完毕
Frank, you're right.
法兰克 你说对了
About the derailment.
他们是要想让车脱轨
They're planning an attempt outside of Arklow.
他们预计在阿克罗镇外行动
Tell them idiots it ain't gonna work.
告诉他们不会成功
That portable derailer. it's worthless.
携带式脱轨器没有用
She already told us.
她已经跟我们说过了
Frank. this is Oscar Galvin. VP of Operations.
他是公司的营运副总我奥斯卡盖文
patched in at his request. open mike.
他要求进入通话 把麦克风打开
Yeah. we're derailing 777. Frank. It's a done decision.
对 我们要让777脱轨 法兰克 这是既成的决定
Like it or not, it's our best option at this stage.
不管你喜不喜欢 这是我们目前最好的选择
There'll be less collateral damage in Arklow.
在阿克罗镇脱轨的损害比较小
It's already being evacuated.
我们已经撤离那里的居民
and we can't let 777 make it to Stanton.
我们不能让777开到斯坦顿
Look. Mr. Galvin. with all due respect.
我无意冒犯
I've been railroading 28 years.
我在铁路已经工作了28年
I'm telling you. we got a real chance to stop this thing.
我们很有机会让列车停下来
No. we already tried.
我们已经试过了
That was from the front. We're long hood lead back.
那是从前面 我们要从后面拉住它
It's a different situation. We got more control now.
情况不同 我们比较能控制列车
What if I cancel the derailer and you fail. Frank?
如果我取消脱轨行动 而你失败了怎么办?
That train will be doing 70 miles an hour
列车会以时速70哩
into that elevated S- curve in Stanton.
冲向斯坦顿
The damage will be 1 00 times worse.
损失会比现在多出百倍
Right. I'm just telling you. the portable derailer is worthless.
但我要说携带式脱轨器没有用
You got too much train traveling entirely too fast.
目前的车厢太多也开得太快
Maybe 1 206 should just stay on it as a backup.
也许可以让1206支援
Look. I am not jeopardizing more personnel and more property
我不会让更多人员或财产受到危害
just because some engineer wants to play hero.
只因为有某个机师想逞英雄
End of discussion!
讨论到此结束!
That train is our property. It's our decision!
那辆列车是我们的财产 由我们做决定!
Now you stop your pursuit or I will fire you!
你现在就停车 不然我就开除你!
Fire. You already did.
你已经开除我了
Already did what?
已经怎么样?
You've already fired me.
你已经开除我了
I received my 90- day notice in the mail 72 days ago.
我已经收到90天的通知信了 就在72天前
Forced early retirement. half benefits.
强制提早退休 红利减半
So you're going to risk your life for us with three weeks left.
所以你只剩3个礼拜 却还是要为我们冒生命危险?
Not for you.
不是为了你们
I'm not doing it for you.
我这么做不是为了你们
Frank. Let me see that thing.
法兰克 把无线电给我
Mr. Galvin. this is Will Colson. your conductor.
盖文先生 我是列车长威尔考森
I'm letting you know. we're going to run this bitch down.
我要告诉你 我们要追到列车
Maybe you didn't hear what I just said. Colson. I will fire you!
你没听到我刚刚说的吗 考森? 我会开除你!
Well. that's too bad. I was just starting to like this job.
真可惜 我才开始喜欢上这份工作呢
God damn it, you listen to me! You son of a bitch! You will be fired!
该死 你给我听着 你这混蛋 你会被开除的!
You're breaking up. Sorry. you're...
讯号不清楚...
- This garbage is... - Sir. I think they're gone.
- 别胡说了... - 长官 我想他们已经收不到了
This is your headache now. Hooper.
现在他们是你的问题了 胡波
Now you get them off the main or consider yourself shit- canned. too!
你得让他们离开主线 不然你自己工作也不保!
I like them.
我喜欢他们
Bring up Beech Siding to Arklow.
让我看进入阿克罗镇的路线图
Take a look behind me, you can see emergency evacuation measures
各位可以看到大家正在紧急撤离
are currently in effect right here in the tiny town of Arklow.
这里是铁轨旁的小镇阿克罗
The lash- up was a no- go.
导引车失败
1 206 to Fuller Yard. Connie. are you there? Over.
1206呼叫富勒调度场 康妮 你在吗?
Frank. I'm real sorry about Galvin.
法兰克 我为盖文的态度道歉
That's okay. Listen. Iisten. Is he off?
没关系 他挂断了吗?
Yeah. he's gone.
对 他挂电话了
Okay. Iisten up.
听着
I'm going to need you to do us a favor.
我要你帮我们一个忙
I need you to keep us posted on the speed and location of 777.
我需要你随时告诉我们777的速度与位置
Location and speed. Over.
位置和速度 完毕
Connie?
康妮?
Frank. 777's 9 miles out of Arklow.
777在阿克罗镇外9哩
You got some catching up to do.
你得快点赶上它
9 miles out of Arklow.
阿克罗镇外9哩
What did you say your wife's first name was?
你说你老婆叫什么名字?
Darcy.
达儿希
So. what was the long story you didn't want to make long?
你说来话长的故事是什么?
I come home from work two weeks ago
2周前有天我回家
and she's texting on the phone.
看到她在传简讯
I ask her who with. she says. "Nobody."
我问她传给谁 她说不重要
I say. "Let me see the phone." She says no.
我要她给我看电话 她不要
This goes on five or six times.
这件事发生了五、六次...
Wait. you're losing me. She's texting...
我没听懂 她传简讯...?
There's this guy we both went to school with.
有个家伙是我们以前同学
He's a cop. he's a PA state trooper.
他现在是州警
He's always had a thing for Darcy. Going way back.
他喜欢达儿希很久了
1206, where are you?
1206 你们在哪里?
1 206 here. Connie. We're just passing milepost 5- 7.
1206回覆 康妮 我们刚刚通过57号哩程标
You're about a mile and a half behind.
你们大约还落后1.5哩
How far out of Arklow is 777?
777离阿克罗镇还有多远?
Seven and a half miles. It picked up speed. You better step on it.
7.5哩 还在加速 你们动作要快
I'm stepping on it. in it. around it and through it. Connie.
我们全速前进中
Thank you. Over.
谢谢 完毕
She's texting on the phone. I keep on asking for it. she keeps on saying no.
她不断传简讯 我一直问她 她一直说没事
She starts to walk away and I grab for it.
然后她走开 我抓住她...
- You hit her? - No. no. no.
- 你打她? - 我没有
I mean. I scared her. but I didn't hit her.
我吓吓她 但我没有打她
Anyway. I drive to this guy's house
总之我开车到那家伙的家
and tell him we need to talk. Iet's take a ride.
说我们得谈谈
He jumps in my truck and starts in with.
他上了我的车后说
"You got it all wrong. We're just friends."
"你误会了 他们只是朋友
Then he stops once he sees
然后他停下来 他看到...
the gun I got sitting on the dash. Oh!
我的车上有枪!
I look him in the eye and say. "She's my wife. You find a new friend."
我看着他 跟他说 "这是我老婆 你去找别人当朋友吧
You pulled a gun on a cop?
你对警察掏枪?
Frank?
法兰克?
Frank. 777 just passed milepost 61.
777刚通过61号哩程标
Thank you. Connie.
谢谢你 康妮
- You want to hear the kicker? - Yes. I do.
- 你想要听更劲爆的吗? - 我想
It wasn't even him that was texting her. It was my sister- in- law.
结果她传简讯的对象不是他 是我的小姨子
Anyway. by the time I got home. his buddy's waiting for me.
总之等我到家 他的同事等候多时
just waiting to serve me with this restraining order.
等着拿禁制令给我
Darcy wouldn't even look at me.
达儿希连看都不看我
So I'm living with my brother.
我跟我哥住
There was a hearing today. The judge ordered a 30- day extension.
今天有一场听证会 法官把禁制令又延长了30天
It's like one day everything's going okay.
本来一切还好好的
and the next. it's all falling apart faster
突然有一天一切都敌了
than you can put it back together.
再也无法复原
Yeah. Never too late. though.
但总是不嫌太迟的
福斯电视台
头条新闱
The plan to derail this 39- car runaway train
这辆39节车厢的失控列车
is just minutes away now.
就要进行脱轨计划了
There's a tremendous amount of activity going on.
现场非常骚动
Will this train be able to be stopped?
这辆火车到底会不会停止呢?
1 206. Connie. We're just passing milepost 6- 2.
1206刚刚通过62号哩程标
Milepost 6- 2, over.
62号哩程标
Still a mile gap. maybe more.
还差一哩多
We're not gaining on her. Frank.
我们不够快
Hold on.
等等
It's just like the shooting range!
这就像去打靶!
All right. here we go! Come on! Let's go! This is it! It's game time!
来了 准备行动!
阿克罗镇北方2.1哩
Remember. we're aiming for the red circular button!
注意瞄准红色的安全闸!
Now!
射击!
Hold your fire! You're shooting the fuel cap. God damn it!
停火 你们打到油箱盖了 见鬼!
Hold your fire!
停火!
We were aiming to disable it by firing shotgun rounds
我们本来要对安全闸开火
at a fuel stop safety switch, and so some shots were fired.
让列车停下来 我们开了几枪...
That safety switch is a mighty small target.
安全闸是很小的目标
And it's right next to a fuel tank.
位置就在油箱旁边
We're not gonna catch it before Arklow.
我们没办法在阿克罗镇前赶上它
Frank. you're closing the gap. You should cut your speed.
法兰克 你们越来越近了 速度放慢
Allow yourself some stopping distance. Just in case.
留一点刹车的距离
No can do. Connie. If we slow down now. we'll never catch it.
没办法 我们现在减速就追不上
Not before Stanton. Over.
在斯坦顿之前追不上
It's your call.
你来决定
However, we have now also learned that two railroad employees
我们得到消息 有二位铁路员工
are now in pursuit of train 777 in a single locomotive.
正搭来一辆火车头追赶777
It is unclear what their plan is...
目前还不知道他们追赶火车的计划...
Connie Hooper for you.
康妮胡波打来了
Did I or did I not tell you to get 1 206 off the main?
我不是要你让1206离开主线了?
I asked them nicely.
我态度很好地跟他们说了啊
You're 1 00% sure that derailer won't work?
你百分之百确定脱轨器没用?
Yes. 1 00%? No.
百分之百不确定
Which one is it?
会成功还是不成功?
- 50- 50. - Pretty funny.
- 机率一半一半 - 真好笑
And if it does?
如果它真的有用呢?
If it does. then we're a wreck on a wreck.
如果有用 我们就惨了
I'm here with FRA official Gene Devereaux.
这位是联邦铁路局的金恩
This train is getting close. How is this going to work?
火车正在逼近 你们要怎么做?
Basically, it works like a ramp.
基本上它的作用就像斜坡
The train comes along,
列车开过来
this piece here will lift the flange and pull it outside the rail.
这个东西就会往上 把列车拉离轨道
That will cause the train to flip over on its right- hand side.
这样列车就会往右翻倒
Son of a bitch won 't even know what hit it.
让列车措手不及
Train's about four minutes out!
列车距离这里4分钟了!
Guys. come on. Get it started!
快发车!
Guys. come on!
大家动作快!
阿克罗镇北方0.5哩
- It has not succeeded! - What?
- 失败了! - 怎么回事?
What in the hell was that?
那是怎么一回事?
That was 1 0 million pounds of train. Mr. Galvin!
那辆列车有1千万吨 盖文先生!
And this is the sound of me saving your ass!
而这是我拯救你的声音!
Frank. do you copy?
法兰克 听到了吗?
Frank?
法兰克?
This is 1 206. Over.
1206号车回覆
You were right. It barely bumped.
你说对了 火车连颠都没颠
Jesus Christ.
我的老天
We're bringing you live coverage right now
我们在现场为各位报导
on what could very well result in one of the worst disasters
这可能会酿成宾州史上
in the history of the state of Pennsylvania.
最大灾难
Now, the particulars are still being examined,
细节还要再调查
but authorities are far more focused
但当局更关注...
on the potential destruction that would result if train 777
777若在斯坦顿脱轨
were to derail in Stanton.
可能的危害
What'd you mean about being married once?
你说自己结过一次婚是什么意思?
Alice. my wife. she died of cancer.
我老婆艾丽丝死于癌症
- Four years ago. - I'm sorry.
- 4年前的事 - 我很遗憾
Me. too.
我也是
Every night. I'd come home. tell her about my day.
每天晚上我回家都会和她分享工作
where I'd been. what I hauled.
我去了哪里 做了什么
who annoyed me.
还有谁让我觉得讨厌
Guess I would have made the evening report. huh?
我晚上应该会跟她说到你
Yes. you would have made it. definitely.
你绝对会说
You should call your wife.
你应该打电话给你老婆
I would. but it's her day off. She's probably sleeping.
她今天休假 大概还在睡觉
Don't make excuses. Wake her up.
别找藉口 吵醒她吧
Been calling for the past two weeks.
我打了二礼拜的电话了
She still hasn't called me back.
她一通都没有回
She won't. You got to call her.
她不会回的 你要自己打给她
Don't you know how that works? You quit too easy.
你搞不懂吗? 你太快放弃了
宾州斯坦顿
Darcy!
达儿希!
I have been calling and calling.
我一直在打电话给你
What is wrong?
怎么了?
As we told you earlier today, those emergency evacuations
如我们稍早报导的
began early this morning as they try to move people out of harm's way.
今早这里有紧急撤离行动 以求居民安全
You get a sense of the perimeter here. You see the firefighters...
这是管制区域 现场的消防员...
Hey. it's me. Yeah. we're on our way.
是我 我们正要出发
Yeah. I know. I'm watching it.
我知道 我正在看
宾州阿克罗
Two railroad employees are presently in pursuit of train 777
有二名铁路员工正驾驶一辆火车头
in a single locomotive.
追赶777号列车
No one seems exactly clear on what their plans are
似乎没人清楚如果他们赶上列车
should they catch up to that train.
打算怎么做
It's Dad.
是爸爸
We have just learned that railroad employee Frank Barnes,
我们刚刚得知法兰克巴恩
a 28- year veteran of the freight company responsible for the runaway,
28年年资 负责列车驾驶...
and Will Colson, a conductor, are now onboard another locomotive.
还有列车长威尔考森都在车上
We're on our way.
我们要过去了
A single locomotive trying to catch up
他们试图追赶...
- to the runaway train. - She's gotta get dressed.
- 失控列车 - 她需要穿衣服
- And get this. They were traveling... - I can tell.
- 为了成功 他们... - 我看到了
She'll be ready in a minute.
她马上过去
... at speeds of up to 70 miles an hour in reverse.
... 以时速70哩反向前进
777 is now just miles away from the significantly...
777号列车现在距离...只有短短几英里路程
Come on. Darcy. Iet's go. Come on. get dressed.
达儿希 快去穿衣服
...more populated town of Stanton.
...人口更加密集的斯坦顿
Let's go. boys!
快走!
距离斯坦顿11哩
Okay. you're getting close.
你们已经接近了
The gap's at a mile and 777 is 1 0 miles to Stanton.
相差1哩 777离斯坦顿有10哩
Now. Iisten. Frank. I got a guy here named Werner from the FRA.
听着 法兰克 这里有位联邦铁路局来的人
Now. I'm inclined to defer to your judgment here. but he...
我不想质疑你的判断 但...
All right. Put him on. We could use all the help we can get.
让他说话 我们有越多协助越好
Just press this and hold to talk.
压住这个键说话
It's about slowing 777 once you've tied on.
你们一接上777就要让它减速
I know conventional wisdom says
我知道传统上...
to just gun it in the opposite direction.
会要你往反方向拉它就好
But you'll have a better shot
但如果你用动力刹车
alternating full throttle with dynamic braking.
跟前进的动力轮替比较会成功
Yeah. but we can't afford to lose counterthrust.
但我们不能失去反推力
What you'll lose in counterthrust
失去的反推力
you'll compensate for in tractive force.
会被牵引力抵销
Are you sure about that?
你确定吗?
Well. it's more of a hunch based on some quick calculations.
这是我快速推算后的直觉
It's a hunch.
是直觉啊
I'm 70 miles an hour and he's giving us a hunch.
我时速70哩 他居然只靠直觉
Okay. Thank you. Put Connie back on. please.
谢谢 请让康妮听电话
It's me, Frank.
是我 法兰克
Yeah. Connie. does this guy know what he's talking about?
康妮 这家伙懂吗?
In a perfect world.
在理想的情况下
yes. I'd say yes.
我会说他懂
In a perfect world. okay.
理想的情况...好吧
We have more now on that runaway freight train in rural Pennsylvania.
在宾州郊区失控的列车后续报导
They've devised an ambitious plan to bring it to a stop.
他们提出一个让列车停止的计划
A single locomotive moves in from behind,
让另外一个车头从后面接近列车
catches up, hooks up and then brakes in an effort to slow it down.
赶上、连结 然后刹车 好让它减速
Passing milepost 7 - 6. Connie. Over.
通过76号哩程标 康妮
You're only a half mile away.
只差半哩了
Half a mile. Out.
半哩 好
Frank. running in reverse. how are you gonna gauge our gap distance?
法兰克 既然是反向 你要怎么判断后方相差的距离?
I could go out there. I could signal you by hand.
我可以到外面给你打手势
At 70 mile an hour?
在时速70哩的时候?
I'm asking. Would it help?
不管 这样有用吗?
All right. Radio and hand signals.
好 用对讲机跟手势
We'll combinate. And be careful.
我们一起合作 你要小心
I will.
我会
And take that vest off. too.
还有 把背心脱掉
- Why? - Just take it off.
- 为什么? - 叫你脱 你就脱
I don't want to look out this window
我不想往后
and see you in that yellow vest. It'll freak me out.
看到你穿着黄背心 我会吓坏
Come on. Will.
接电话啊 威尔
Pick up. Come on.
快接电话
This is Will. Leave me a message.
我是威尔 请留言...
Damn!
该死!
Ten cars. Frank!
距离十节车厢!
Affirmative. Over.
我知道了
All right. here she comes!
接近了!
Three cars?
相差约三节车厢?
Three cars steady. Copy.
三节车厢 收到
All right. Steady, steady!
稳住!
Two cars?
距离两节车厢?
Yeah. two cars. Copy.
两节车厢 收到
Steady. Over.
稳住
Keep it coming. keep it coming!
再来 再来!
Keep it coming!
再来!
Steady. steady!
稳住 稳住!
Will Colson is trying to hook up 1206
威尔考森试着连结1206
- with 777. - Oh. my God.
- 和777 - 我的天哪
Something has gone terribly wrong.
出了严重的差错
Will. what was that?
威尔 怎么回事?
The grain car blew a seal!
谷粒被吹飞了!
Are we tied off?
我们连结上了吗?
Will, what's going on?
怎么回事?
Right now we are looking at live pictures of this rescue operation.
现在看到的是救援行动的现场画面
Are we tied off?
我们连结上了吗?
No. Frank. it didn't work. Our knuckle closed!
没有 连结器关上了!
Will. use hand signals! Hand signals!
威尔 跟我比手势 用手势!
We tied on?
连结上了吗?
We're good! We're good!
好了 好了!
What?
你说什么?
Oh. shit.
该死
Frank. the pin didn't fall!
法兰克 连结器没有落锁!
Say again. The what?
再说一次 什么?
Will. are we tied on?
我们接上了没?
It's not gonna work. The pin didn't fall.
不行 连结器没有落锁
What?
什么?
The pin didn't fall! It's not locking!
连结器有问题 没有锁上!
All right. well. Iook.
好 听着
Try and get down there. see what you can do. Be careful!
下去看看可以怎么办 你要小心!
Be careful.
你要小心
Will!
威尔!
It's not slowing down. It's gaining speed right now.
列车没有减速 反倒加速了
He's reaching down, trying to couple...
他到下面去连接...
Will. can you read me?
威尔 你收得到吗?
He's gone!
他不见了!
Will Colson is down. We do not see him.
威尔考森滑下去了 我们看不见他
Chopper 43, can you zoom in?
43号直升机能将镜头拉近吗?
- We do not see the conductor, Colson. - Come on. baby.
- 我们看不到列车长威尔考森 - 加油 宝贝
Will. can you read me? Will!
威尔 你收得到吗? 威尔!
Chopper 43, zoom in. There he is. Will Colson.
43号直升机 拉近镜头 看到他了 威尔考森
As he struggles to pull himself up,
他挣扎着把自己拉上来
Iooks like Will Colson is in trouble.
看来威尔考森有麻烦了
The train is coupled.
二辆车连接了
I'm now being told that the connection has been made.
我听说二辆车已经接好了
It looks as though this train is now attached.
看起来列车连接上了
1 206 has been successfully attached to 777.
1206已经成功接上777
But it looks like Will Colson is injured.
但威尔考森似乎受伤了
You all right?
你还好吗?
I'm great.
我很好
Hey. hey. don't touch that! Don't touch that boot!
不要碰触靴子
Here. just wrap it up with this.
用这个缠住就好!
Wrap it real tight. all around.
整个都缠好 紧紧缠住
You okay?
你还可以吗?
I'm all right. I'm all right.
没事 没事
Barnes and Colson have caught up to the runaway train.
巴恩和考森赶上了这辆失控列车
Darcy. come on. Come on.
达儿希 走吧
But the train continues to speed in excess of 75 miles an hour,
但火车依旧以75哩的时速
heading to Stanton.
往斯坦顿前进
Connie. how far we got?
康妮 现在距离多远?
How far to Stanton? Over.
距离斯坦顿多远?
4 miles. You guys are doing great.
还有4哩 你们做得很棒
You're cutting it close. though.
但时间紧迫
How's Will?
威尔怎么样?
He's... He's different. Over.
他很惨 完毕
Ready for a little tug- of- war?
准备好拔河了吗?
Let's do it.
来吧
Match our speed with theirs.
我们要试着跟列车的速度一致
- Frank. we're gonna snap right off. - No. we're not. we're not.
- 我们会扯断连结 - 不会的
We're just stretching. that's all. We're just stretching.
只是会拉扯而已 没事的
Here in Stanton,
斯坦顿
the evacuation procedures continue for the entire town.
持续撤离全镇居民
This is the town where that mainline train track turns into an elevated curve.
主线轨道会在这里升高进入弯道
They say there is virtually no chance
据说这辆高速的...
this speeding, out- of- control train
失控列车几乎不可能
will make it through that curve.
通过这个弯道
We should be slowing down.
我们应该要减速
Which we're not.
但是没有
Shoot.
该死
Go to the dynamic. Alternate full throttle.
改用动力刹车 跟全速前进轮替
Christ! Those cab brakes are getting a workout.
那些刹车快被操斓了
...because of the highly toxic nature of the cargo.
...因为载运有害物质...
Come on. Frank.
法兰克 加油
Come on. baby.
减速吧 宝贝
What's our speed?
我们速度多少?
We're under 50.
低于50哩了
Connie. how far away?
康妮 目前距离多远?
3 miles. FRA's got men on the ground ready to hop onboard
3哩 我已经安排人手待命
as soon as you guys get it under 20.
你们一减速到20他们就会跳上车
All right. Tell them. be ready to hop. Over.
叫他们准备跳吧
Shoot!
该死!
- What is it? - We're gaining speed.
- 怎么回事? - 速度加快了
Consist is too heavy. We're being dragged.
列车太重 我们被拖着走了
Connie!
康妮!
I'm here. Frank.
我在这里 法兰克
We're gonna be coming in too hot.
我们的速度太快了
Let them know.
通知联邦铁路局的人
The limit on that curve is 1 5.
弯道的速限是15哩
I don't know if you can take it much faster. maybe 20. 25. max?
快太多就过不去 顶多20到25还可以?
We may not have a choice. Just tell them it's gonna be real hot.
我没有选择 告诉他们我们的速度会很快
What about the braking on the freight cars?
车厢的刹车可不可以用?
Good. good.
很好
All right. I'm on it.
我来
Just sit down. No. no. I've got it. Sit tight.
坐下 我去 你坐好
I'll go out. Sit down. No. in fact. come here.
我到外面去 你过来吧
You sit here. I'll go out.
你坐在这边 我到外面去
Just keep it at four.
维持在4
You all right? Take it easy. Yeah.
可以吗?
Hold that dynamic at a four. Four.
握住刹车把手推到4
Integrate it with the throttle if you have to.
必要时跟前进动力搭配
Hold it at a four. integrate the throttle.
维持在4 跟前进动力搭配
Burn the block out. it doesn't matter.
尽量操刹车块 不重要
Hey. don't get sentimental on me.
别突然感伤起来
Makes me think I'm gonna die. Just hold that four.
你让我感觉我快死了 你握好就对
Come on. Frank.
加油 法兰克
AWVR officials have no comment.
铁路公司不予置评
Barnes is attempting to manually brake the last car of 777.
巴恩要动手 将777最后一节车厢煞住
He's actually running on top of the grain cars and jumping...
他在列车项上迸走...
Way to go. Frank. Let's go. Frank.
法兰克 加油
Looks like 777 is slowing down.
看来777的确减速了
We understand this is some sort of
我们明白 这么做
an attempt to try and stop the train.
是为了让列车减速
Yes! Come on. come on! You can do it!
好样的 加油! 你可以的!
Will. how fast you going?
你们现在速度多少?
34.
34哩
All right. we're dropping. 33.
我们在减速了 33哩
The railroad spokesman just confirmed he is...
铁路公司发言人确认...
- Think it'll work? - ...attempting to slow 777
- 这样管用吗? - ...巴恩现在动手
by manually braking each car.
把各车厢刹车开启
Theoretically.
理论上可行
Provided that locomotive's independent brake holds out.
只要车头的独立刹车没问题
We continue to bring you live coverage of this breaking news event
继续在斯坦顿现场报导
from the town of Stanton.
头条新闱
Emergency management officials have created this perimeter.
紧急小组划出管制区...
This is the police. Get off the roof.
这是警察 请撤离屋项
You are being asked to evacuate for your own safety.
为了你们的安全 请马上离开
Shit!
该死!
Frank!
法兰克!
Yeah. I hear you. I hear you!
我听到了!
We just lost our brakes!
我们的刹车坏了!
Looks like the brakes have blown.
看来刹车爆了
Shit!
见鬼!
Frank! Frank. you all right?
法兰克 法兰克 你没事吧?
I'm here. Will. What happened?
我没事 威尔 怎么回事?
We're picking up speed again.
我们又加速了
Can you still slow it down? We're almost at the curve.
你能不能设法让它减速? 我们快到弯道了
Frank. our engine block's overheated.
法兰克 引擎已经过热了
I don't think those hand brakes are gonna
我认为手动刹车
have the muscle to stop this thing.
也没办法减速
We're creeping up fast.
速度实在太快
All right. well. just hang on to the independent.
你用独立刹车吧
I'll tell you when.
我会告诉你时间点
Elevated and strictly Class 2, speed restricted to 1 5 miles per hour.
火车进入第二级的高架铁轨 这里的时速限制是15哩
Impact with at least three of these buildings
正下方的三栋建筑
directly below will be unavoidable,
会无法幸免
as will contact with all the fuel storage tanks situated here.
这里的燃料槽也一样
Will? Will.
威尔? 威尔
We're all right. we're all right.
我们没事
but we're picking up speed again.
但速度又加快了
Will!
威尔!
We're coming into the curve! Get ready!
我们要进入弯道了 准备了!
Will! Hit that independent!
威尔 拉独立刹车杆!
Hit that independent as hard as you can!
用力拉刹车杆!
Frank. we're gonna rip right off.
我们会脱轨
Got no choice.
我们没有选择
Will! Hang on!
威尔 撑住!
Hit it! Hit it again!
拉! 再拉一次!
Now!
就是现在!
Frank. you all right?
法兰克 你没事吧?
We made it! We made it! We're through the curve.
我们成功了 通过弯道了 他们成功通过弯道了
777 made it. It made it through the Stanton curve.
777成功了 已经通过弯道
777 is through the Stanton curve,
777已经通过弯道
but by no means out of trouble.
但问题还没有结束
777 is gaining speed. It is out of control and has to derail.
777正在加速 失去控制 必须要让它脱轨才行
Frank Barnes and Will Colson will be
法兰克和威尔
the victims of the biggest rail disaster
会成为东北区史上
in the history of the northeast.
最严重铁路意外的受害者
It looks like Frank Barnes is making an all- out effort.
看来法兰克巴忍拼了
Good job.
太好了
This is a remarkable effort now to get to the front of 777.
了不起 他要前往777的车头
Frank!
法兰克!
We're at... We're at 60. and we're going to hit 80 in no time!
我们速度到60了 很快就会到80哩!
He's not gonna make it.
他过不去
Looks like the gap between cars has stopped him.
看来车厢间的距离让他止步了
You can do it!
继续啊!
But the train continues to speed in excess of 75 miles an hour.
列车持续以75哩的时速前进
Frank! Frank!
法兰克 法兰克!
Will. we got a problem here.
有问题了
I don't think I can make it.
我做不到
Oh. God.
天啊
There's Ned!
是奈德!
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
不可思议 不可思议
Hello. Ned. it's Connie.
奈德 我是康妮
I'm kind of busy right now. Connie. I'll call you back.
我现在有点忙 康妮 我再打给你
Hey!
嘿!
Come on!
跳啊!
Hop in the back of the truck!
跳到卡车后车厢!
Connie? Connie. is that truck for us?
康妮 那辆卡车是来帮我们的吗?
Yes. it is. Will. You can do this.
是 威尔 你做得到
Will, you can do this!
你可以的!
Come on!
加油!
...停止列车 在主线...
Looks like he's trying to synchronize
看来他们想要获得
the speed of the pickup with the train.
与火车同步的速度
Do it. you pussy! Jump in the back!
快跳 不要犹豫 跳到后面!
Yes! Yes!
好样的!
Yeah!
And look at what's happening now.
真是千钧一发
The red pickup racing to the front of 777.
红色卡车要把他载到车头
Come on. Will.
加油
Frank!
法兰克!
Go! Just go! Go. go. go!
快去 快往前!
Go. go. go!
快点 快去!
Go. go!
冲吧!
Ned Oldham is running out of parallel road.
奈德快要没有路可以跑了
Come on. Will.
加油 威尔
Drive. Ned!
奈德 快开啊!
He will attempt to board this train.
他企图登上列车
- Come on! - Shit!
- 快点 - 该死
God damn it! I overshot it!
见鬼 过头了!
Come on.
加油啊
There it is. kid! Do it!
快跳啊 快!
Come on. jump! Do it! Jump!
跳啊 快点 跳!
Yes!
太好了!
Go. Dad!
爸 加油!
Yeah! Yeah!
好样的!
Yeah! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Oh. my God!
天啊!
Go! Go. Will!
加油 威尔 加油!
Will Colson successfully making it into the cab,
威尔考森成功进入驾驶室
now in control of 777.
777受到控制了
Chopper 43 over this remarkable aftermath.
43号直升机捕捉到这重大的一刻
We're talking about the heroic work of two men,
我们看到这二人的英雄事迹
Frank Barnes and Will Colson.
法兰克巴恩和威尔考森
Southern Pennsylvania will always be indebted to them.
南宾州会永远感激他们
未接来电 达儿希
Judas Priest. we did it! We did it!
阿弥陀佛 我们做到了!
I knew once we got you up there. we'd do it. Ned Oldham.
我知道把你弄上去就可以搞定 我是奈德奥德曼
It's all about precision. Good job. kid.
精准度最重要 小子 做得好
- Your foot's hurt. He cut his foot! - I think it's broken.
- 你的脚受伤了 他割伤脚了 - 我觉得骨折了
He cut his foot! Let's get some medics!
他割伤脚了 找医护人员过来!
Get over here. kiddo.
小子 过来
- Ned! - You!
- 奈德 - 你问!
Ned. were you worried?
奈德 你当时很担心吗?
Was I worried? Nah. Not really.
担心? 不 还好啊
It's all about precision. I wouldn't have undertaken such a task...
精准度最重要 天将大任于斯人...
Just got off the line with corporate.
我刚刚接到公司的电话
Oh. yeah?
是吗?
"Debt of gratitude." Blah. blah. blah.
说什么我们很感谢你啊
Same here. Felt pretty good. actually.
我也是 其实感觉满爽的
Yeah. it did. actually.
是啦
...bringing it to a successful conclusion.
...让事情完美的结束
What was your first reaction when you realized what was happening?
你发现这件事时有什么反应?
I felt I was in my comfort zone.
我觉得自己有能力应变
What'd they say about your job?
他们对你的工作有什么说法?
They said it's mine if I want to keep it.
我想的话可以留任
They'd be stupid not to give it to you.
不给你工作才蠢吧
Yeah. That's what I told them.
我也这么说
Said they better think about giving me a better one. too.
他们最好给我一个更好的位置
- How about me? - How about you?
- 那我呢? - 你怎样?
- As you can see, the result was a positive. - Ned...
- 结果成功了 - 奈德...
Do we have any better of an idea as to how this happened?
你知道这一切是怎么发生的吗?
Well, the thing that happened...
这个嘛...
- Thank you very much, Ned. - Everybody, this is Ned Oldham.
- 谢谢你的回答 奈德 - 我是奈德
To answer that last question...
要回答这个问题...
Sorry. I wonder if you can help me.
抱歉 你能帮我一个忙吗?
Connie? I can't decide
康妮? 我无法决定
which one of you I'm gonna kiss first.
要先亲你们哪一个
Me.
当然是我啊
Problem solved.
问题解决了
Go get him. Connie.
来吧 康妮
All right. Bring it on.
过来吧
...to Frank Barnes and Will Colson,
...感谢法兰克巴恩和威尔考森
the engineer and the conductor whose actions...
机师跟列车长的壮举...
Your daughters?
你女儿吗?
Chopper 43, over and out.
43号直升机 完毕
When the song come on in the club
Turn it up Turn it up, turn it up Rewind!
法兰克巴恩升官后开心退休
The dance train is coming back again
他领到全额红利
Extravaganza, you should run and tell a friend
威尔考森与达儿希婚姻美满
第二个小孩即将出生
Kings and queens are posted at the bar
康妮胡波升迁担任营运副总我
Bucking down It's time to take it off
取代盖文的职位
Walk that walk Walk
Show me how you move it
雷恩史考特还健在
Can you walk that talk? Talk
Put some snap into it
Time to show it all
杜伊目前从事速食业
The spotlight is on you You better... Let's go!
Work, work, work, work
Work, work, work
You better shake that thing like a donkey
And go hard for it You better work
You better swing from a paw like a monkey
'Cause big girls get down on the floor
And make it jiggle, jiggle, jiggle You ain 't know
Ain 't no shame It's the name of the game
Now everybody down to the floor Here we go!
We got the rhythm of the beat
We got the rhythm of the hands
Let's get the rhythm of the feet
Jump in, jump out
Jump in, jump out Here we go
Work, work, work
Work, work, work You better work
仅此纪念荷莉诺顿及爱德利玛托